<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>






<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Jitender Datta</title>
        <link>https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/</link>
        <description>Collections of writings of Mr. Jitender Datta</description>
        <generator>Hugo 0.69.0 https://gohugo.io/</generator>
        
            <language>en</language>
        
        
        
        
            <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</copyright>
        
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 14:35:57 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate>
        
            <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss&#43;xml" href="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/rss.xml" />
        
        
            <item>
                <title>Suggested Prayers</title>
                <link>https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/posts/suggested-prayers/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/posts/suggested-prayers/</guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 14:07:56 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</copyright>
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some of prayers that I suggest one can make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God, give me strength and knowledge so I always stay happy, peaceful, and full of love; and never get angry or upset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God, give me strength and knowledge so I always stay positive and stay away from negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God, give me strength and knowledge to completely accept whatever comes in my life, so I may happily keep working hard with positive thoughts, words, and actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suggested food prayer:&lt;/strong&gt; God, thank you for giving us this food. We pray that this food gives us strength and wisdom so we may stay happy, peaceful, loveful, and stable; and be able to help thos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/categories/spirituality/">spirituality</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/tags/spirituality/">spirituality</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/tags/prayers/">prayers</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>All I’ve Learnt, in a Nutshell</title>
                <link>https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/posts/what-i-have-learned/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/posts/what-i-have-learned/</guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 14:06:09 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</copyright>
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;What’s important at all time is that you keep doing good. You need to do good even when you think that others do not deserve your good, and even if others talk negative to you or about you. Eventually, it is never between you and them. At the end, it is only between you and the almighty anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow these simple rules to improve your life:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Happily accept everything that comes your way as a payback of your own earlier actions. Sometimes, these might be from your earlier lives, of which you may have absolutely no knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In every situation, think, speak, and do only positively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay away from all negativities all the time, especially anger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you sincerely implement these rules for even one month, you will start experiencing increased positivity and reduced negativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to be happy, only look at the positive points of others, and never at their negatives. With some people, you may have to spend more time to find their positive points. Remember that it is not their fault that you are taking time to find their positive points; it is only your lack of thoughtfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be flexible with all points that are physical, which is basically anything you can see or touch. You should be completely firm with the good points and thoughts you have developed. These include positivity, happiness, love, and peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to keep increasing your physical assets, but increasing your positive qualities requires more attention. Your positive qualities are far more superior when compared to your physical assets. After all, physical assets can help you only till your body is breathing, whereas positive qualities will keep helping your soul even after this life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we’ve understood that our anger hurts just us. Anger may develop because of various external factors or people, but the fact is that I create my own anger and it hurts only me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to how we can avoid getting angry, one method that works for me is this. I believe that all situations &amp;ndash; the way one talks to me, the expressions one uses to interact with me, or any problem that comes my way &amp;ndash; are actually the results I am getting back owing to my own previous karmic accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no control over any such situation. Every statement that someone makes, I have no control over it; every action that someone takes, I have no control over it. What’s in my control is my being stable to train my mind, so I do not allow it to get angry and upset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another method that works well is my belief that all other people are completely right according to their own points of view views, even though they may be different from mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you start winning over your own anger, you will be calm. You will be able to think, speak, and do better. You will also be able to interact with others in more positive ways. Please make extra efforts to ensure that even a little anger or negativity does not enter your thought process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to evaluate yourself and determine what you want to be. Assume you want to be happy, peaceful, and full of love. Then, try to keep this in mind most of the time and hopefully, in few days, you will be with all these qualities all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another step requires developing strength and resilience. This helps you stay the way you want to be, no matter how situations around you develop. So, if someone gets angry with you, you will maintain your qualities and remain calm, happy, peaceful, and full of love. If you stay strong, other’s anger will not be able to throw you off balance. Eventually, you will spend your entire remaining life staying happy, peaceful, and full of love. Once that happens, you will like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, if we keep thinking positive, and never think negative about anyone, we will keep spreading positivity in this world. We will keep increasing our own qualities and keep helping others. Our thoughts, words, and actions must revolve around love, peace, purity, bliss, knowledge, happiness, and good strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/categories/spirituality/">spirituality</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/tags/spirituality/">spirituality</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/tags/learning/">learning</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Basics of Spirituality</title>
                <link>https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/posts/basics-of-spirituality/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/posts/basics-of-spirituality/</guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 14:02:39 &#43;0200</pubDate>
                
                <copyright>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</copyright>
                
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Here, I will try to explain the meaning of some of the words I use. These are not official definitions. I am describing them in simple terms, so you may understand the ideas when I use these words. The words are listed alphabetically, and not in any order of importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;actions&#34;&gt;Actions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people feel that actions refer to whatever we do, speaking included. We should understand that actions also involve our thoughts. Of the three, thinking is the most powerful, because thoughts travel to others much faster than speech or physical actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider this example. I go to meet someone with a well-prepared speech. However, I may end up conveying any negativity from my mind even before I begin speaking. Here’s a good saying to suit the situation &amp;ndash; if it is not worth saying or doing, it is not worth thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-happy&#34;&gt;Being Happy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I’m right in saying that everyone wants to be happy. You should also understand that if your happiness is dependent on others and external factors, you will be happy only some of the time, not all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My suggestion is you should mold your thoughts in a way that your happiness never depends upon others or any external factor. Only then can you expect round-the-clock happiness. This is a very important aspect to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I am available, ask me for ways in which you can be happy from within. If you cannot reach me, watch videos of Shivani from the “Happiness Unlimited” series, where she talks about different aspects that affect happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-and-doing&#34;&gt;Being and Doing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While what you do in your life is important, what’s more important is how you feel. Every time you experience anger, sadness, jealousy, or hatred, your body produces bad chemicals that have a detrimental effect on your mind and body. Bear in mind that each thought you have affects every cell in your body. Try to steer clear of negative thoughts and emotions at all times. If something goes wrong, try to correct it by staying calm, understanding that it is a result of your own karmic accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-full-of-love&#34;&gt;Being Full of Love&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being full of love, or loveful, means that love is your quality. Your love for all people does not depend on their qualities. You love everyone simply because you are full of love, and love is your quality. You may have heard that God loves you no matter what. This is a great way to explain being loveful, because God is full of love. Try to give more love when you feel that someone least deserves it, because that is the time when he or she needs it the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-peaceful&#34;&gt;Being Peaceful&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being peaceful is simply being happy and staying calm, and not being upset. If you come by a seemingly negative situation, use your thought process to your benefit. Accept the situation as a present fact and as the result of your earlier karmic accounts, give benefit of doubt to others, and look for positivity in the given situation. By doing this, you remain peaceful and, therefore, will be able to determine the most appropriate way forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-pure&#34;&gt;Being Pure&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purity means that your thoughts, words, and actions are in one line, and are positive. You should always remain calm and composed. This way, everyone, including yourself, will know that you are dependable, and that your responses always stay positive and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;being-strong&#34;&gt;Being Strong&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get more strength, you need almighty’s help. This is easy to achieve by meditating in the morning, when your mind is at its best. I define strength as the power to keep your thought process positive and calm, without it being disturbed by others or any external factor. Rome, of course, was not built in a day, which is why you need to control your thought process with the help of positive thinking and by getting more positive knowledge, which will take some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;belief-systems&#34;&gt;Belief Systems&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review your belief systems. Think about all your beliefs. Spend some time on each belief. Keep them as part of your belief system only if your mind analyses them to be right and they give you positivity. Some of the beliefs that increase your happiness include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You love everyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone has the right to form their own opinions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You accept each and every situation as correct and accurate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the beliefs that have negative effects on your happiness and peace include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anger is necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Praising others will have a negative effect on them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Controlling others will make you powerful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;competition&#34;&gt;Competition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not try to compete and compare yourself with others. Every person comes with a body that is controlled by a soul, and no two souls in the entire world can be same. All souls have a baggage of varied karmic accounts and they will keep performing according to their own sanskars and karmic accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand this in physical terms, any competition between two people is rather like a doctor competing with an engineer based on technical knowledge. The only person you should compete with is yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think good for everyone. In doing so, you are improving yourself. You do not wait for others to think good for you. Change is the law of nature. Try your best to keep changing only in the positive direction with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;criticism&#34;&gt;Criticism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If something goes wrong because of your or someone else’s actions, do not blame or criticize anyone. Fact remains that it is the result of some of your present and previous actions, and the results are never in your control. You may learn some lessons from your previous actions for the future. However, any additional time spent in thinking about previous situations is a waste. Use your energies only for seeking solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;detachment&#34;&gt;Detachment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most religions teach us to be detached. However, being detached does not mean we should stop being concerned about our surroundings and other people. Let me explain with two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A surgeon comes to operate on a patient. Typically, he is wearing a gown, gloves, and a mask. He takes these precautions so that the patient does not get his germs and vice versa. This is detachment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are with a very dear relative who is involved in an accident and is crying in pain. If you also start crying and become upset, you will be of no help. If you stay detached, your mind remains calm, and you might be able to help in different ways such as calling emergency personnel, offering comfort, and providing any possible first aid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;difficult-situations&#34;&gt;Difficult Situations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a situation arrives, accept it as a payback of your previous actions. Do not blame anyone else. Do not keep wasting your time and energy in thinking about the situation. It is already here. Get busy in finding solutions about the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a situation is bothering you, remember that good solutions are ones that tell you what you should be doing, and not what others should be doing or should have done. Here, actions mean your words, your physical actions, as well as your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many instances, thoughts are more powerful than words and actions. This is why peaceful thoughts help you find appropriate solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think that a situation is powerful, you become weak. If you gain control over your emotional reactions, you become stronger and are able to find better solutions as a master. Try your best to react in a way that gives thoughtful benefit of doubt to any other person who, in your opinion, has done something negative to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;healing&#34;&gt;Healing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Address and heal each and every discomfort as early as possible. Otherwise you keep living with discomfort, and it becomes worse with time. Healing is basically explaining to your own mind (self-counseling) that the situation at hand is rightfully here, and you need to find out how to live your life positively and happily with the situation. Think only about what you should be doing, and not about what others should have done or should do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;karmic-account&#34;&gt;Karmic Account&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balance sheet of everything you do and its results is referred to as your karmic account. It is just like a bank account. The more positivity or negativity you add, the more positivity or negativity you end up building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During your present life, all your thoughts, words, and actions, along with their results, keep adding to your karmic accounts. You then take the remaining balance with you to your next life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone takes birth based on previous karmic accounts. At birth, we also bring our accumulated personalities with us. Every situation in my life is based on my old karmic accounts. In addition, all the thoughts, words, and actions I use to handle different situations contribute toward my future destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this life, my remaining karmic accounts will have a direct bearing on my subsequent rebirths. During the journey of my life, it is important for me to work hard in obtaining things that make my body comfortable. However, I need to be particularly careful toward two other aspects. These include karmic accounts and my personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the things which provide material comfort will have no effect on me after death. My karmic accounts and personality, on the other hand, will have an effect on all my subsequent lives. This is why I should be more careful about my positive thoughts, words, and actions, so I may keep improving my destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;living-in-the-present&#34;&gt;Living in the Present&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the thinking about the past or the future is wasteful and/or negative. We should devote all our concentration only to the present. While thinking about the present, we need to start by accepting every situation – big or small – at that moment. We should remember that all existing situations are results of our own past actions. Once we have accepted the present, we need to evaluate how our thoughts, words, and actions will be the most positive and productive in handling a situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;making-choices&#34;&gt;Making Choices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider an example surrounding your choice of being happy, which involves someone scolding you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your first alternative is to genuinely give benefit of doubt to the other person and consider that he or she may have some erroneous information about you. You offer blessings, pray for the individual to be more knowledgeable, and be very cooperative and friendly. There’s a good chance that that person will become your well-wisher in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you become angry and respond by scolding right back. This increases the negativity between both, and it is highly unlikely that that person is going to become your well-wisher in future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By staying calm and positive, and using proper responses, you can improve your present and future destiny. Try your best to stay happy, peaceful, and loveful – all of the time. If, even for a small amount of time, you fail, try to find out what you need to do to be happy again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not criticize or blame anyone or any situation. Using positive benefit of doubt, accept every situation. This way, you will develop additional strength to handle the situation and you will develop more happiness, peace, and strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any situation that comes to you is only the effect or result of your own previous actions. You are able to modify your future destiny based on how you respond to any situation. No matter what actions you take, the results will always be based upon your actions as well your own sanskars and karmic accounts. Keeping all these factors in mind, someone has correctively said, “You don’t get what you want, you get what you are (deserve)”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;personality&#34;&gt;Personality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each soul has three distinct faculties – mind, intellect, and personality. Thoughts are created in the mind. They are processed and interpreted by the intellect, and then come into action. All the results of these actions are stored as impressions, and the personality of every soul is created by such stored impressions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;process-of-destiny&#34;&gt;Process of Destiny&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that is it is I who completely creates and modifies my own destiny. My thoughts generate feelings, feelings generate attitude, attitude generates lines of action, repeated actions generate habits, and all my habits form my personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever a situation arises, I respond using my thoughts, my words, and my actions, all based on my personality. This, in turn, creates my destiny. Given my understanding of the concept of karma, as of today, my destiny is completely fixed and it is purely based on the karma I have done as of today. From this point forward, based on my personality, I can start modifying my actions, and thus, modify my destiny. Once I understand this, it becomes easier for me to modify my destiny and move in the desired direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any time, a good astrologist can predict your destiny and he may be completely correct in his predictions at that time. His predictions are based upon all your karmas up to that time. You can modify your future destiny through different types of karmas after the time he makes the prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purpose-of-this-life&#34;&gt;Purpose of This Life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do my best to keep improving qualities of my soul. During my interactions in this life, I try my best to help others and also improve the qualities of their souls. This way, I will improve my destiny and help others in doing the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positive-and-negative-qualities&#34;&gt;Positive and Negative Qualities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increase positive qualities such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Happiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reduce negative qualities such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hatred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jealousy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Criticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attachments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ego&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positive-thinking&#34;&gt;Positive Thinking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Positive thinking is not about expecting the best to happen. It is about accepting that whatever happens is as appropriate and correct as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;soul&#34;&gt;Soul&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who am I? It is good for everyone to understand this as early as possible. I am a soul that is indestructible – this is one of the key statements of the Gita. I keep travelling in different bodies. In this life, I am living in a human body that was named Jitender Datta.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The soul does not have any physical properties. It carries sanskars and the complete balance sheet of all earlier karmic accounts. The original qualities of every soul include happiness, love, peace, bliss, knowledge, purity, and power/strength. Through the course of our actions in the bodily form, we have compromised with our original qualities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;success-and-happiness&#34;&gt;Success and Happiness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone wants to be happy. Success, in physical items, is based on several aspects. For instance, if you study hard, you are likely to succeed in your exams. However, real success is for you to be happy no matter what results you get after you do your work happily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your happiness is based on any situation or individual, you cannot control your happiness, because it is dependent on external things that are beyond your control. Once you practice creating happiness within yourself and do not depend on external things, you can learn to create unlimited happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;process-of-learning&#34;&gt;Process of Learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of learning is rather straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obtain knowledge (gather information)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditate (churn the information)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice the information in your daily actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share the information – by sharing you become more knowledgeable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore all ideas and do not discard any positive idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suggestions&#34;&gt;Suggestions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At times, it might be appropriate to offer suggestions to others. In such situations, make sure you develop positivity in yourself before trying to develop it in someone else. Be kind and, if required, forgiving, before and while offering your suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it is good to offer suggestions, be careful about two important aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If someone does not accept your suggestion, don’t let it affect your mental state adversely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your suggestion should never imply that you are trying to change the other person. Whenever you try to improve or change anyone, you clearly imply that the person is doing something wrong, and you want it done right. Remember that no one ever does anything wrong according to their own points of view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is okay to make critical suggestions about specific points, but not when directed at other people. It’s much like the old saying that suggests hating the sin and not the sinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never try to change others. Modify yourself. After all, would you try to carpet the whole world, instead of simply protecting your feet by wearing shoes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
                
                
                
                
                
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/categories/spirituality/">spirituality</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                        
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/tags/spirituality/">spirituality</category>
                                
                            
                                
                                
                                
                                    <category domain="https://riteshjn.github.io/jtdatta/tags/basics/">basics</category>
                                
                            
                        
                    
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
